<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mario Carrion</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/</link><description>Recent content on Mario Carrion</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mariocarrion.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GopherCon 2018: Day 3 Conferences Day Two</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/08/29/gophercon-2018-day-3.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/08/29/gophercon-2018-day-3.html</guid><description>Welcome to the Second day of conferences at GopherCon 2018!
The day started with Writing Accessible Go by Julia Ferraioli, she covered a topic relevant to my professional experience: Accessibility. Obviously all the points she mentioned in her talk made a lot of sense from the Accessibility point of view, however what I found more interesting about this talk was how those points not only improve accessibility but also make the final code much more clearer and easier to understand, and how those recommendations are conventions in Go that are encouraged, like using short names for variables for example.</description></item><item><title>GopherCon 2018: Day 2 Conferences Day One</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/08/28/gophercon-2018-day-2.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/08/28/gophercon-2018-day-2.html</guid><description>Today was the official first day of GopherCon. The conferences day to put it someway (but was my second one!). I arrived early because I assumed the breakfast lines will be similar to the ones we had yesterday for lunch, and considering it was only &amp;ldquo;half&amp;rdquo; the expected attendees I really wanted to make sure I avoided not having enough food.
After having breakfast, and before the first talk, I was able to explore the exhibitors booths, I got some really cool Gopher pins from the Microsoft booth:</description></item><item><title>GopherCon 2018: Days 0 and 1</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/08/27/gophercon-2018-day-1.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/08/27/gophercon-2018-day-1.html</guid><description>Day 0 Next planned trip after San Francisco was Denver! To attend GopherCon for the first time ever!
It&amp;#39;s almost time to board! #GopherCon #GopherConDay0 pic.twitter.com/Tz6eMIu7wh
&amp;mdash; Mario Carrion (@mariocarrion) August 26, 2018 We took off early Sunday morning because I was attending the Architecture &amp;amp; Domain Modeling with Go kit workshop next day and because we wanted to explore a the city and the surroundings before kicking off everything GopherCon next morning.</description></item><item><title>Vacationing in San Francisco</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/08/22/vacationing-in-san-francisco.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/08/22/vacationing-in-san-francisco.html</guid><description>I can&amp;rsquo;t recall exactly when was the last time I took a break longer than a few days. Either way I know for sure one thing: San Francisco marks the start of our long vacation! Interestingly enough we had planned this trip since last year for one special reason!
That special reason was for attending a wedding, we could not miss it: two good friends were getting married! It was a nice event that brought back nice memories when we went there five (or six?</description></item><item><title>Go Tip: Generating JSON Web Key Sets</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/08/06/go-generating-json-web-key-sets.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/08/06/go-generating-json-web-key-sets.html</guid><description>Previously I blogged about using ActiveDirectory and JWT with Go, well this quick tip is somehow related to that post, it&amp;rsquo;s for generating JSON Web Key Sets that should help for creating a real valid JSON or for testing local-only values.
There&amp;rsquo;s a full example showing this in action, feel free to explore the repo.
This example uses the great go-jose package by Square, the final snippet code looks like this:</description></item><item><title>Go Tip: Swagger UI &#43; CORS</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/07/26/go-swagger-ui-cors.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/07/26/go-swagger-ui-cors.html</guid><description>Previously I blogged about using Dredd for verifying that the generated swagger.json is correct (from the Swagger 2.0 specification perspective, that is) now let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at another tip for making sure the final API works correctly when using Swagger UI for manual inspection.
There&amp;rsquo;s a full example showing this in action, feel free to explore the repo.
It is most likely you already enabled CORS on your web API.</description></item><item><title>Dell DW15 meets Macbook Pro</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/07/23/dell-dw15-macbook-pro.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/07/23/dell-dw15-macbook-pro.html</guid><description>Last year I was upgraded to a new Macbook Pro, I was using a Macbook Air for the last 3 years, in the beginning I was a bit worried because I did not want to be forced to use the Touch Bar on a daily basis, luckily enough I was assigned the Macbook Pro 13&amp;rdquo; which does not come with that! What a relief!
This new Macbook Pro comes with two USB-C ports which, not surprisingly, represent carrying new adapters with you all the time, those adapters are for external output, USB 2.</description></item><item><title>Go Tip: Azure Active Directory &#43; JWT</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/07/16/azure-active-directory-jwt.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/07/16/azure-active-directory-jwt.html</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s cover how to use Azure Active Directory (for authentication) and JSON Web Tokens (for authorizing) your enterprise users in Go!
By the way this is not your classic How to use Go with JWT (search golang jwt on Google, or any other search engine for that) this is more focused on using specifically the actual Azure Active Directory service for getting the JSON Web Token and then using that to authorize your API.</description></item><item><title>Finished Reading: The 80/20 Principle</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/07/01/the-80-20-principle.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/07/01/the-80-20-principle.html</guid><description>Although I was expecting a bit &amp;quot;more&amp;quot; from &amp;quot;The 80/20 Principle&amp;quot;, I still can see the practical use of this principle. pic.twitter.com/y9nQuMfm1Q
&amp;mdash; Mario Carrion (@mariocarrion) June 26, 2018 I&amp;rsquo;ve been curious about this principle and book since I heard about it for the first time. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expected the, mostly, financial content of the book which makes sense after you complete it, but it does drag a bit in the beginning.</description></item><item><title>I&#39;m ready for July 2018</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/06/27/im-ready-for-july-2018.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/06/27/im-ready-for-july-2018.html</guid><description>I just realized that __14 years and 2 days ago__ I published my first ever blog. My last college year and I was planning to write a Blogger-like system (hah!). Time really flies. pic.twitter.com/y9NGk5DlgH
&amp;mdash; Mario Carrion (@mariocarrion) June 28, 2018 It is really crazy that today, 14 years and 2 days ago, I started blogging. My first post describes the naive idea of rewriting Blogger.
The &amp;ldquo;funny&amp;rdquo; thing is that a month later I would be completing an ActiveView-like library, written in PHP4 using the newly introduced support for classes, called HTML2PHP.</description></item><item><title>Go Tip: Code Coverage</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/06/20/code-coverage-in-go.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/06/20/code-coverage-in-go.html</guid><description>Code coverage in Go is included in the toolchain and it is as simple as appending -coverprofile to the usual go test command, kind of like using:
go test -coverprofile=cover.out &amp;lt;package-name&amp;gt; Assuming all tests pass, then you should get an output similar to:
ok &amp;lt;package-name&amp;gt; 0.046s coverage: &amp;lt;XY.Z&amp;gt;% of statements Where XY.Z is the actual code coverage percentage. Notice that the coverprofile file, cover.out, can be used for generating a more human friendly output, like HTML, with:</description></item><item><title>Finished Reading: Talk like TED</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/05/25/talk-like-ted.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/05/25/talk-like-ted.html</guid><description>Just finished reading &amp;quot;Talk like TED&amp;quot;. Fascinating and inspiring book. pic.twitter.com/xf2NLS8kER
&amp;mdash; Mario Carrion (@mariocarrion) May 25, 2018 Talk like TED: The 9-Public Speaking Secrets of the World&amp;rsquo;s Top Minds is a book written by Carmine Gallo and published by St. Martin&amp;rsquo;s Press in 2014.
This paragraph is fascinating. Taken from “Talk like TED” pic.twitter.com/ttGEH9WgOy
&amp;mdash; Mario Carrion (@mariocarrion) May 17, 2018 Talk like TED provides 9 secrets, or tips, TED speakers have used over the years to properly deliver their message while keeping the audience engaged.</description></item><item><title>Finished Reading: Software Design X-Rays</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/05/11/software-design-x-rays.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/05/11/software-design-x-rays.html</guid><description>Just finished reading &amp;quot;Software Design X-Rays&amp;quot;. Really interesting book. pic.twitter.com/qzXlVRmmDw
&amp;mdash; Mario Carrion (@mariocarrion) May 11, 2018 Software Design X-Rays is a book written by Adam Tornhill and published by The Pragmatic Programmers in 2018.
I was interested in reading this book since I saw the Beta version a few months back, gladly my interest was rewarded and it did not disappoint. It left me with a new way of looking at Software Development and showed me a measurable way to look at bottleneck code and hot spots.</description></item><item><title>Finished Reading: Architectural Patterns</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/04/30/architectural-patterns.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/04/30/architectural-patterns.html</guid><description>Just finished reading &amp;quot;Architectural Patterns&amp;quot;, last book of April. It covers a lot of Software Architecture-related patterns. Long read. pic.twitter.com/k0itAZuaED
&amp;mdash; Mario Carrion (@mariocarrion) April 30, 2018 Architectural Patterns is a long book written by Pethuru Raj, Anupama Raman and Harihara Subramanian. It was published by Packt in 2017 and it covers all kind of software patterns, from your well-known classic Software Design Patterns to the more general Enterprise Patterns, and includes as well some specific patterns applicable to SOA and Microservices.</description></item><item><title>GothamGo 2018</title><link>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/04/27/gotham-go-2018.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mariocarrion.com/2018/04/27/gotham-go-2018.html</guid><description>I had a great time last time I went to Gotham Go in 2016, I went two days, first day was the Advanced Workshop and second day was the conferences day; sadly I missed it last year, but this year I was surprised they changed the dates, they moved it from fall to spring which aligned correctly to my busy schedule. I was really looking forward to attending this year.</description></item></channel></rss>